Kiss your nuts goodbye.
Ice Age: The Meltdown is a animation, family, comedy
film directed by Carlos Saldanha.
Diego, Manny and Sid return in this sequel to the hit animated movie Ice Age.
This time around, the deep freeze is over, and the ice-covered earth is
starting to melt, which will destroy the trio's cherished valley.
The impending disaster prompts them to reunite and warn all
the other beasts about the desperate situation.
Manny (voice), played by Ray Romano.
Sid (voice), played by John Leguizamo.
Diego (voice), played by Denis Leary.
Ellie (voice), played by Queen Latifah.
Crash (voice), played by Seann William Scott.
Eddie (voice), played by Josh Peck.
Ice Age: The Meltdown is a 2006 American animated adventure
comedy film produced by Blue Sky Studios.
The second in the Ice Age film series, it was directed by Carlos Saldanha and features Ray Romano, John Leguizamo, Denis Leary, and Chris
Wedge reprising their roles from the first film, with Seann William Scott, Josh Peck, and Queen Latifah joining the cast.
In the film, Manny, Sid, and Diego attempt to escape an
impending flood, during which Manny finds love.
Ice Age: The Meltdown premiered on March 19, 2006, at Grauman's Chinese Theater in
Hollywood, and was released in the United States on March 31, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and grossed $667
million, becoming the third highest-grossing film of 2006.
Four further follow-ups were released―four sequels of which being Dawn of the Dinosaurs in 2009, Continental
Drift in 2012, and Collision Course in 2016, plus a spin-off, Adventures of Buck Wild in 2022.
A sixth installment, Boiling Point, is set for release in 2027.
The film explores themes of mammoth, sloth, ice age, barrier ice, ice melting.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.